Guide to the Richard L. Purdy Collection of Thomas Hardy
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Thomas Hardy Correspondence, 1873-1971; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  - OUTGOING LETTERS
    - Blomfield, Arthur, 1888-1900 (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Bowker, R. R., 1881 Jun 4 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Broadley, Alexander, 1906 Mar 4 (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Buckle, George Earle, 1901 Aug 31 (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Christie, Mary, 1883 Apr 11 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Clifford, Lucy, 1909-13 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Clodd, Edward, 1893-1920 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Colbourne, Maurice, 1919 Dec 11 (Box 3, Folder 130)
    - Colles, William Morris, 1893 Mar 26 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - Cotton, J. S., 1886 Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - D'Anvers, Miss [Nancy Meugens], 1877-98 (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - Deland, Margaret, 1892 Jun 21 (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - Dewar, George, 1911 Feb 12 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Donaldson, S. A., 1913-14 (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Dugdale, Constance, 1915-25 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Dugdale, Edward, 1914-23 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Dugdale, Eva [envelope only], 1910 Dec (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Dugdale, Emma, 1912-1926 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Du Maurier, George, 1880 Feb 21 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Durrant, Wilfrid S., 1909 Jun (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Ellis, Havelock, 1883 Apr 23 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Ellis, Stewart M., 1917 Dec 27 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Evans, Alfred H., 1909-10 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Foote, George W., 1910 Jun 12 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Forbes-Robertson, Ian, 1899 Jan 2 (Box 3, Folder 147)
    - Ford, Ford Madox, 1909 Jan 31 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - Forrest, Sir George, 1907-25 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Foster, Ernest, 1892 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 150)
    - Foster, Joshua J., 1895 Apr 20 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - Gardiner, Alfred G., 1908 Mar 19 (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - George Bryan & Co., 1904 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Gissing, George, 1886-95 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Graham, Stephen, 1924 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Greenhill, George, 1880 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 156)
    - Grein, J.T., 1890 Jul 24 (Box 3, Folder 157)
    - Grove, Agnes Geraldine, Lady, 1895-99 (Box 3, Folder 158)
      See also: Series I, Writings of Others, Box 2 folder 103
    - Grove, Agnes Geraldine, Lady, 1900-22 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Hall, Hammond, 1904 Oct 26 (Box 4, Folder 160)
    - Hardy, Emma, 1900 Nov 6 (Box 4, Folder 161)
    - Hardy, Florence, 1905-24 (Box 4, Folder 162-63)
    - Hardy, Katharine, 1897 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Harper & Bros., 1878 Jun 24 (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Head, Henry and Ruth, 1922 May 21 (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Heinemann, William, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 167)
    - Hill, Frank, Mrs., 1879 Jul 18 (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Hinkley, Rufus, 1911 Jul 18 (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Hopkins, Arthur fragment [photostat], 1878 Feb 20 (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Subscription to "Hospital", 70 Hamilton Terrace, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Hunt, Mrs. Holman, 1906-07 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - Jarvis, C.W., 1890 (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Jennings, Louis, 1874 Sep 12 (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Jeune, Francis, 1891 Apr 30 (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Jeune, Mary (Lady St. Helier), 1886-1923 (Box 4, Folder 176-77)
    - Key, Samuel Whittell, 1904 Mar 2 (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Knowles, James, 1904 (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Lane, John, 1891-92 (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Leslie, Lady Constance, 1912 Aug 13 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Little, Stanley, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Locker, Arthur, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 183)
    - McClure, Samuel S., 1890 Sep 13 (Box 4, Folder 184)
    - Macquoid, Thomas, 1875-84 (Box 4, Folder 185)
    - Macmillan, Frederick, Sir, 1911 Jul 2 (Box 4, Folder 186)
    - EMPTY FOLDER (Box 4, Folder 187)
    - Marston, Edward, 1888-93 (Box 4, Folder 188)
    - Massingham, Henry W., 1907 Jul 1 (Box 4, Folder 189)
    - Maxwell, Gerald, 1904 Sep 5 (Box 4, Folder 190)
    - Maxwell, William, 1927 Oct (Box 4, Folder 191)
    - Meugens, Nancy
      See: Miss D'Anvers, Box 3 folder 133
    - Milman, Lena, 1893 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Milne, James, 1910 Sep (Box 4, Folder 193)
    - Moore, George, 1910 Dec 26 (Box 4, Folder 193a)
    - Morgan, John H., General, 1920 Jun 28 (Box 4, Folder 194)
    - Morley, John, 1885 Nov 20 (Box 4, Folder 195)
    - Moule, Handley, Reverend, 1880 Feb 11 (Box 4, Folder 195a)
    - Moule, John, 1907 Sep 21 (Box 4, Folder 196)
    - Mundy, Harriott, 1897 Oct 16 (Box 4, Folder 197)
    - Osgood, James, 1890 Nov (Box 4, Folder 198)
    - Panton, Jane Ellen, 1886-1921 (Box 4, Folder 199)
    - Paul, Charles Kegan, 1878-79 (Box 4, Folder 200)
    - Perry Mason & Co., 1883 Nov 5 (Box 4, Folder 201)
    - Payne, James, 1886 Jun 16 (Box 4, Folder 202)
    - Pinero, Sir Arthur Wing, 1912-14 (Box 4, Folder 203)
    - Pollock, Frederick, 1893 Apr 4 (Box 4, Folder 204)
    - Pouncy, Harry, 1907 Feb 3 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - Quilter, Harry, 1888-93 (Box 4, Folder 206)
    - R & R Clark & Co., 1925 Dec 9 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - Ralston, William Ralston Shedden-, 1881 Oct 20 (Box 4, Folder 208)
    - Rees, Leonard, 1920 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 209)
    - Rideing, William H., 1886 Dec 13 (Box 4, Folder 210)
    - Ritchie, Anne Isabella Thackeray, [1888] (Box 4, Folder 211)
    - Sampson Low, Marston & Co., 1894 Sep 8 (Box 4, Folder 212)
    - Shaylor, Joseph, 1909 Oct 6 (Box 4, Folder 213)
    - Sheridan, Mary, 1889 Jan 4 (Box 4, Folder 214)
    - Shorter, Clement, 1904 Apr 18 (Box 4, Folder 215)
    - Smith, Evangeline, 1910 Jul 27 (Box 4, Folder 216)
    - Soundy, Margaret, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 217)
    - The Spectator, 1905 Apr 25 (Box 4, Folder 218)
    - Spurgeon, Arthur, 1921 Dec 13 (Box 4, Folder 219)
    - Stone, Henry, 1914 Feb 13 (Box 4, Folder 220)
    - Strang, William, 1910-14 (Box 4, Folder 221)
    - Symons, Arthur, 1896-1921 (Box 4, Folder 222)
    - Thomas, William Moy, 1875-89 (Box 4, Folder 223)
    - Thomson, Winifred, 1889-1900 (Box 4, Folder 224)
    - Tillotson & Son, 1889-91 (Box 4, Folder 225)
    - Tinsley, William, 1873 (Box 4, Folder 226)
    - Tomson, Arthur, 1889-1902 (Box 4, Folder 227)
    - Turner, Thackeray, 1897 Sep 25 (Box 4, Folder 228)
    - Udal, John Symonds, 1910 Sep 30 (Box 4, Folder 229)
    - Vinall, Charles G., 1881 Oct 20 (Box 4, Folder 230)
    - Watts-Dunton, Theodore, 1912 Dec 25 (Box 4, Folder 231)
    - Windle, Bertram, 1896 Sep 28
      See: Series I, Black's Guide to Dorset, Box 1, folder 9
    - Wright, Joseph, 1902 Dec 18 (Box 4, Folder 232)
    - Unidentified, 1882-1910 (Box 4, Folder 233)
    - Christmas Card, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 234)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Allhusen, Dorothy
      - to Florence Hardy, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 235)
      - to Snaebjörn Jónsson, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 236)
      - to Margaret Soundy, 1942 Jan 22 (Box 5, Folder 237)
    - Ballantyne, R.M. (Box 5, Folder 238)
      - To Sir George Douglas, 1880-86
    - Barrie, J.M. (Box 5, Folder 239)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1929-35
    - Baring-Gould, Sabine (Box 5, Folder 240)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1891
    - Beerbohm, Max (Box 5, Folder 241)
      - to Florence Hardy, n.d.
    - Brittain, Vera (Box 5, Folder 242)
      - to Margaret Soundy, 1937 Jul 24
    - Cholmondeley, Mary (Box 5, Folder 243)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1913 Nov 1
    - Cockerell, Sydney C. (Box 5, Folder 244)
      - to Mr. Roscoe [E. Haigh?], 1929 Apr 3
    - De la Mare, Walter (Box 5, Folder 245)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1931 Mar 23
    - Douglas, Sir George (Box 5, Folder 246)
      - to Mrs. Turnbull, 1888-1904
    - Flower, Newman
      - to Eva Dugdale, 1958 Dec 15 (Box 5, Folder 247)
      - to Miss Dugdale, 1939 Nov 29 (Box 5, Folder 248)
    - Forster, E.M. (Box 5, Folder 249)
      - to Eva Dugdale, 1937 Oct 20
    - Gosse, Edmund (Box 5, Folder 250)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1891-95
    - Grand, Sarah (Box 5, Folder 251)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1914 Apr 22
    - Hardy, Emma
      - to Lady Agnes Geraldine Grove, 1907 Dec 9
        See: Series I, Writings of Others, Box 2 folder 103
      - to Mrs. Alfred Pope [photocopy], 1912 Feb 9 (Box 5, Folder 252)
      - to Clement and Mrs. Shorter, 1900-12
    - Hardy, Florence
      - to Dorothy Allhusen, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 253)
        See also: Series I, "Dorothy Allhusen's Appeal Letter", Box 3 folder 114
      - to Howard Bliss, 1928-34 (Box 5, Folder 254)
      - to Howard Bliss, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 255)
      - to Edward Clodd, 1910-16 (Box 5, Folder 256)
      - to Sydney Cockerell, 1914-27 (Box 5, Folder 257)
        See also: Series I, "The Fiddler's Story and a Jingle on the Times," Box 1, folder 26; "The Play of Saint George," Box 2, folder 69; and "To Shakespeare after Three Hundred Years," Box 2, folder 86
        See also: Series V. Sydney C. Cockerell Papers - Correspondence, Box 21, folders 643-57
      - to Arthur Wing Pinero, 1929-30 (Box 5, Folder 258)
      - to E. Haigh Roscoe, 1929 Apr 4 (Box 5, Folder 259)
      - to Unidentified [unused condolence response form letters], 1928 (Box 5, Folder 260)
    - Hardy, Katharine (Box 5, Folder 261)
      - to Eva Dugdale, 1939-40
    - Hoare, Lady Alda (Box 5, Folder 262)
      - to F.E.H. [removed from the copy of The Thoughts of the Emperor M. Aurelius by Antoninus, trans. by George Long, 1862], 1936 Dec 19
    - Jónsson, Snaebjörn (Box 5, Folder 263)
      - to Dorothy Allhusen, 1940-58
    - Lawrence, Montagu (Box 5, Folder 264)
      - to Margaret Soundy, 1971 Oct
        [with Bible tract by Geo. Cutting]
    - Lawrence, T.E. (Box 5, Folder 265)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1923, 1933
    - Lawrence, T.E. (Box 5, Folder 266)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1923-35
        [Photocopies made for Miss Cooper Willis before Max Gate Sale]
    - Maartens, Maarten (Box 5, Folder 267)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1894 Aug 10
    - McCutcheon, George Barr (Box 5, Folder 268)
      - to Crosby Gaige, 1928 Jan 31
    - Moule, C.W. (Box 5, Folder 269)
      - to Sydney Cockerell, 1918 Aug 17
    - Moule, G.H.
      - to [Constance?] Dugdale, 1940 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 270)
      - to Miss Dugdale, 1948 Dec 20 (Box 5, Folder 271)
    - Philpotts, Eden
      - to Florence Hardy, 1937 Jun 19 (Box 5, Folder 272)
      - to Margaret Soundy, 1937 Oct 18 (Box 5, Folder 273)
    - Pinto, Vivian de Sola (Box 5, Folder 274)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1928 May 12
    - Rhys, Ernest (Box 5, Folder 275)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1895-1925
    - Ricketts, Charles (Box 5, Folder 276)
      - to A.E. Drinkwater, 1915 Mar 29
    - Sharp, William (Box 5, Folder 277)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1895 Dec 21
    - Soundy, Margaret (Box 5, Folder 278)
      - to Unidentified, 1935 Jul 12
    - Sturgis, Howard (Box 5, Folder 279)
      - to Sir George Douglas, 1896 Nov 13
    - Terry, Marion to Emma Hardy, 1885
      See: Series III - Scrapbook, Box 7 folder 332e
    - Tomlinson, H.M. (Box 5, Folder 280)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1930 Sep 17
    - University College of the Southwest (Box 5, Folder 281)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1937 Oct 20
    - Wharton, Edith (Box 5, Folder 281a)
      - to Dorothy [Allhusen?], 1934 Apr 24
      - [removed from copy of A Backward Glance ]
    - Willis, Irene Cooper (Box 5, Folder 282)
      - to Eva Dugdale, 1935 Apr 7
    - Yeats Brown, Francis (Box 5, Folder 283)
      - to Florence Hardy, 1933 May 30
- Thomas Hardy Association Material, 1861-1978; Series III; 1; (2 boxes)
  Series III is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Address Book - Florence Hardy, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 284)
  - Address Book - Florence Hardy, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Autograph page, 1892 (Box 6, Folder 286)
    [includes Thomas Hardy, Marion Terry, George E. Buckle, C. Moberly Bell, and Genie Norreys] [from Dorothy Allhusen]
  - Bookplates [created for Max Gate Library by Sydney Cockerell] [with clippings], 1928-38 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Calling Cards
    - Mr. Thomas Hardy, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 288)
    - Mrs. Thomas Hardy, n.d.
  - Cinema Programme - Far from the Madding Crowd - Cinema House, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Diary - Eva Dugdale, 2 leaves, 1928 Jan (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Diary - Florence Hardy [2 leaves with locks of hair of "Sweet Peggy"], 1896 Jul 14 (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Diary - Florence Hardy [33 leaves], 1918 (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Drawings
    - "Brighton April 3, 1863" by Thomas Hardy [with note from C.J. Dugdale], 1863 Apr 3 (Box 6, Folder 293)
    - "Imaginary View of Tintagel Castle at the time of the Tragedy" by T.H. (photograph), 1925 May (Box 6, Folder 294)
    - Map of Tess's country by Thomas Hardy for Lorin Deland, 1895 (Box 6, Folder 294a)
    - "Mine Field in Kirkland" by Emma Hardy [photograph] (Box 6, Folder 295)
    - Thomas Hardy by W.R. [i.e. William Rothenstein], print, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 296)
    - "St. Kneighton's Kieve nr. Boscastle" by T.H., ca. 1872 (Box 6, Folder 297)
    - "Tilly's Whim" by T.H., 1876 Feb 14
  - Etching of Thomas Hardy by Francis Dodd for The Dynasts [facsimile], n.d. (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Floor plan for Antique Building by T.H., n.d. (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Lithograph of poster for performance of The Dynasts by Charles Ricketts done for the Cigarette Fund, signed by Ricketts and Thomas Hardy, 1914 (Box 6, Folder 299a)
  - Notebook - Eliza Bright Nicholls "Lectures on the Tabernacle", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Paintings
    - Thomas Hardy by Reginald Eves [oil on canvas], 1923 (Box 6, Folder 300a ptg)
  - Photographs
    - Antell, Polly, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 301)
    - Arundel Terrace, Trinity Road, Upper Tooting, 1967 Jul (Box 6, Folder 302)
    - Gold Hill, Shaftesbury, by H.E. Foster, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 303)
    - Higher Bockhampton, Birthplace of Thomas Hardy, ca. 1940s (Box 6, Folder 304)
    - Dorchester Views, 1969-75, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 305)
    - Hardy, Florence, at Seaside, ca. 1911 (Box 6, Folder 306)
    - Hardy, Florence, informal snapshots [including Margaret Soundy?], ca. 1920-35 (Box 6, Folder 307)
    - Hardy, Florence, portraits, ca. 1880s, 1920 (Box 6, Folder 308)
      See also: Oversize, Box 27, folder 825
    - Hardy, Florence, with J.M. Barrie at performance of Peter Pan, 1932 Dec (Box 6, Folder 309)
    - Hardy, Florence, with T.E. Lawrence, [ca. 1923-24] (Box 6, Folder 310)
    - Hardy, Kate and Henry [including Whitby family and William Butt], ca. 1914-30 (Box 6, Folder 311)
    - Hardy, Thomas, artists' renderings [includes William Strang], ca. 1893-1927 (Box 6, Folder 312)
    - Hardy, Thomas - burial collage, 1928 (Box 6, Folder 313)
    - Hardy, Thomas - bust by Serge Youriévitch [one signed by T.H.], 1929 (Box 6, Folder 314)
    - Hardy, Thomas, dinner portrait with group after performance of Tess at Weymouth, 1924 Dec 11 (Box 6, Folder 315)
    - Hardy, Thomas - informal snapshots, ca. 1920s (Box 6, Folder 316)
    - Hardy, Thomas - portraits, ca. 1861-90 (Box 6, Folder 317)
    - Hardy, Thomas - portraits, ca. 1900-27 (Box 6, Folder 318)
      See also: Oversize, Box 27, folder 826
    - Hardy, Thomas - postcard portraits, ca. 1900-28 (Box 6, Folder 319)
    - Hardy, Thomas, receiving honorary degree at Cambridge, 1913 Jun 11 (Box 6, Folder 320)
    - Hardy, Thomas - tomb, Stinsford, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 321)
    - Hardy, Thomas, viewing The Oresteia at Max Gate with others, 1924 Jul 1 (Box 6, Folder 322)
    - Hardy, Thomas, with Bishop of Salisbury, et al., 1919 (Box 6, Folder 323)
    - Hardy, Thomas, with Gwen Ffrangçon- Davies and Philip Ridgeway, ca. 1927 (Box 6, Folder 324)
    - Hardy, Thomas, with Emma Hardy and Nellie Gosse, Weymouth, 1890 Sep 9 (Box 7, Folder 325)
    - Hardy, Thomas, with H.R.H. the Prince of Wales, ca. 1925 (Box 7, Folder 326)
    - Hardy, Thomas, with men in academic regalia, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 326a)
    - Max Gate, ca. 1900-78 (Box 7, Folder 327)
    - Nicholls, Eliza Bright [includes 1 ambrotype], ca. 1880-1900 (Box 7, Folder 328)
    - Statue of Thomas Hardy, Dorchester [with Sir James Barrie], 1947 Oct 25 (Box 7, Folder 329)
    - Talbothays Lodge, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 330)
    - Wessex [Wessie], dog at Max Gate, 1926 (Box 7, Folder 331)
    - Widow Jethway's Cottage, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Prints
    - Etching of "Thomas Hardy's Birthplace near Dorchester" by Leonard Patten, signed [inscribed to Richard L. Purdy by Florence Hardy, 1929 Aug 30], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332a)
    - Etching of God talking to Thomas Hardy ("But Mr. Hardy, if you only knew all the circumstances...") by Will Dyson, signed, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332b)
    - Etching of Thomas Hardy by Alfred Bennett, signed, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332c)
    - Etchings of Thomas Hardy (two different poses) by William Strang, signed, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332)
  - Royalty statements, Macmillan & Co., 1943-44 (Box 7, Folder 332e)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Dugdale, Constance - Dugdale-Hardy wedding and married life, 1914-57
      See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 827
    - Dugdale, Constance - Thomas Hardy death and burial, 1928 Jan
      See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 828
    - Marion Terry and "Far From the Madding Crowd" production, 1882-87
      - [includes letter from Marion Terry to Emma Hardy, 1883]
      - See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 829
  - Sketch Album [from Drollie to Marjorie] Contains sketch of Roman Amphitheatre, Dorchester, by T.H. 1910 and Egdon Heath (watercolor) by Mary Hardy 1910 (Box 7, Folder 333)
  - Stationery from Hardy's desk, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 334)
  - Theatre Programs
    - "The Day After the Fair" - Lyric Theatre, 1972 Oct (Box 7, Folder 335)
    - "A Desperate Remedy" - Corn Exchange, Dorchester, 1922 Nov 15-17 (Box 7, Folder 336)
    - "A Desperate Remedy" - King's Hall, Covent Garden, 1922 Nov 21 (Box 7, Folder 337)
    - The Play of "Saint George" - Dorsetshire, 1921 Apr (Box 7, Folder 338)
    - "The Queen of Cornwall" - Dorchester, 1923 (Box 7, Folder 339)
    - "The Queen of Cornwall" - Glastonbury Festival, 1924 Aug (Box 7, Folder 340)
    - "The Queen of Cornwall" - King George's Hall, 1924 Feb 21 (Box 7, Folder 341)
    - "The Queen of Cornwall" - Hill Crest, Boars Hill, Oxford, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 342)
    - "The Return of the Native" - Corn Exchange, Dorchester, 1920 Nov 17-18 (Box 7, Folder 343)
    - "Tess of the D'Urbervilles" - Barnes Theatre, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 344)
    - "Tess of the D'Urbervilles" - Corn Exchange, Dorchester, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 345)
    - "Tess of the D'Urbervilles" - Duke of York's Theatre, 1929 Aug (Box 7, Folder 346)
    - "Tess of the D'Urbervilles" - New Theatre, 1946 Nov 26-30 (Box 7, Folder 347)
    - "Tess of the D'Urbervilles" - Pavilion Theatre, Weymouth, 1929 Dec 11 (Box 7, Folder 348)
    - "Under the Greenwood Tree" - The Cripplegate Institute, 1910 Dec 1 (Box 7, Folder 349)
    - "The Woodlanders" - Cripplegate Institute, London, 1913 Dec 8 (Box 7, Folder 350)
  - Time book for "The Dynasts" - Volume 2: Miss Lillah McCarthy and Mr. Granville Barker, 1914 Jul 1
    See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 830
  - Watercolor - Dove Cote at Athelhampton by Thomas Hardy, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 351)
  - Watercolor - Sydney Cockerell in his study by D.H. [photograph], 1951 (Box 7, Folder 352)
  - Watercolor - "Eliza Bright Nicholls aged about 14 years", n.d. (Box 7, Folder 353)
- Thomas Hardy Research Material, 1855-1981; Series IV; 5.5; (13 boxes)
  Series IV is subdivided into 9 subseries, each of which is arranged alphabetically.
  - ARTICLES
    - Bowden, Ann, "The Thomas Hardy Collection" The Library Chronicle of the U. of Texas, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 354)
    - Bowker, R. R. "London as a Literary Center", printed version, Harper's New Monthly Magazine, 1888 Jun (Box 8, Folder 354a)
    - Boyd, Ernest, "A New Way with Old Masterpieces..." Harper's Monthly Magazine, 1925 Jul (Box 8, Folder 355)
    - Brooks, Philip, "Notes on Rare Books," The New York Times Book Review, 1941 Jul 20 (Box 8, Folder 356)
    - Brown, T.J. "English Literary Autographs XIX," The Book Collector, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 357)
      [with correspondence between Brown and Richard Purdy, 1956]
    - Cassell's Weekly tribute issue, including "Thomas Hardy in his 84th Year" by Henry W. Nevinson; "A Hardy Dialogue" by E. Hallam Moorhouse; and "Lionel Johnson on the Wessex Novels", 1923 Jun 20
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 831
    - "The Colby Collection of Hardy Letters," The Colby Mercury, 1934 Dec 1 (Box 8, Folder 358)
    - Cox, J. Stevens ed. "T.J. Wise, Mrs. Hardy & Hardy's Manuscripts," pamphlet, (photocopy), Toucan Press, Guernsey, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 359)
    - Douglas, George, "Thomas Hardy: Some Recollections and Reflections," The Hibbert Journal, 1928 Apr (Box 8, Folder 360)
    - Dron, T.M. "Durnovarian Reminiscences," Dorset Year Book, 1929 (Box 8, Folder 361)
    - du Parcq, J.P.; "A 'Disclaimer' Disclaimed", n.d. (Box 8, Folder 362)
    - "Editorial Notes," The London Mercury, 1928 Feb (Box 8, Folder 363)
    - Ellis, S.M. "Thomas Hardy: Some Personal Recollections," The Fortnightly Review, 1928 Mar (Box 8, Folder 364)
    - Freeman, John, "The Early Life of Thomas Hardy," The London Mercury, 1929 Feb (Box 8, Folder 365)
    - Freeman, John, "Thomas Hardy," The London Mercury, 1928 Mar (Box 8, Folder 366)
    - Garstang, A.H. "The Humour of Thomas Hardy," The Fortnightly Review, 1928 Feb (Box 8, Folder 367)
    - Gwynn, Stephen, "Ebb and Flow - A Monthly Commentary," The Fortnightly Review, 1928 Mar (Box 8, Folder 368)
    - EMPTY FOLDER (Box 8, Folder 369)
    - Hoeber, Arthur, "George Meredith and Thomas Hardy" (Box 8, Folder 370)
    - Holland, Clive, "Thomas Hardy and Wessex," The Bookman, 1928 Feb (Box 8, Folder 371)
    - Holland, Clive, "Thomas Hardy as I Knew Him," The Landmark, 1928 Feb (Box 8, Folder 372)
    - Hone, J.M. "The Poetry of Mr. Hardy," The London Mercury, 1922 Feb (Box 8, Folder 373)
    - Hutchins, Patricia, "Thomas Hardy and Some Younger Writers," draft with letter, 1968 Oct 11 (Box 8, Folder 374)
    - Jerome, Jerome K. "When I was an Editor," Harper's Monthly Magazine, 1925 Jul (Box 8, Folder 375)
    - King, George, "Thomas Hardy: Novelist and Poet," The Cornhill Magazine, 1928 Mar (Box 8, Folder 376)
    - "The Lost Novel of Thomas Hardy: The Poor Man and the Lady," The Bookman's Journal Vol. VII, no.4, 1927 [i.e. 1928] (Box 8, Folder 377)
    - Mayoux, J. J. "L'amour dans les romans de Thomas Hardy," Revue Anglo-Américaine [part one only], 1928 Feb (Box 8, Folder 378)
    - "Mr. Hardy's Poems" The Saturday Westminster Gazette, 1919 Dec 6
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 832
    - Mooers, Horatio T. "Hardy's Women and the Spirit of the Wessex Novels," Exlibris, 1925 Jan (Box 8, Folder 379)
    - Murry, John Middleton, "Notes and Comments," The New Adelphi, 1928 Mar (Box 8, Folder 380)
    - "Note of Acquisition of Three Letters of Thomas Hardy," The Campbellian, 1958 Apr (Box 8, Folder 381)
    - Parker, W.M. "My Visit to Thomas Hardy..." The Cornhill Magazine, 1929 Feb (Box 8, Folder 382)
    - "A Rhymed Criticism of 'Wessex Poems'," The Bookman, 1899 Apr (Box 8, Folder 383)
    - Shorter, Clement King, "A Literary Letter: The American Critics and the English," The Sphere, 1925 Sep 19
      See: Oversize, Box 28, folder 833
    - Tresillian, Michael, "Thomas Hardy at St. Juliot," Cornish Magazine, 1966 Feb (Box 8, Folder 384)
    - Van Doren, Carl, "Thomas Hardy," The Outlook, 1928 Jan 25 (Box 8, Folder 385)
    - Weber, Carl J. "Thomas Hardy's 'Song in The Woodlanders '," English Literary History, 1935 Nov (Box 8, Folder 386)
    - Weber, Carl J. "A Hardy Thought," letter to the editor of The Saturday Review, 1940 May 25 (Box 8, Folder 387)
    - Whibley, Charles, "Thomas Hardy," Blackwood's Magazine, 1913 Jun (Box 8, Folder 388)
    - Williams, Orlo, "Far From The Madding Crowd," The New Adelphi, 1928-29 (Box 8, Folder 389)
  - AUCTION AND BOOKSELLERS' CATALOGS
    - American Art Association
      - Collection of George Barr McCutcheon, 1925 (Box 8, Folder 390)
      - Library of B. George Uligio, 1931 (Box 8, Folder 391)